yet
can the pioneering machine learning in
neural nets
or zip pictures and think that's good
a okay
so I gave a talk here a couple years ago
and the first
10 minutes was there will be an overview
what I said there
and then I'll talk about the new stuff
um the new staff consists of a better
learning module
I'll show you learns better also
different things like
arm learning how images transform
learning how people walk
and learning object recognition so the
basic learning module
consists of some variables represent
things like pixels
need to be binary variables when I'm
some variables represent
these a latent variables they're also
gonna be binary and there's a bipartite
connectivity
so these guys and connect to each other
and that makes it very easy
if I give you the states that the
physical variables to further states
that the
in variables they're all independent
governor visible variables
it's not directed graph and the
inference procedure says
the probability of turning on him unit
HJ I'm given this visible back to be
is the logistic function at the total in
but it gets from his brilliance
so very simple to infer that Merkel's
I'm giving hidden variables we can also
in for the visible variables were simply
and if you want to if we put some weight
on the connections
we want to know what this model believes
we can just go backwards and forwards
inferring all hidden variables in Parel
that all these ones that for a long time
and then you'll see examples are the
kinds of things I'd like to believe
may move money is going to be to get
into like to believe the kinds of things
that actually happened so this thing is
governed by an energy function
but idk in the weights on the
connections the energy of a visible
person back to
is the sum over all connections all
the wait if both visible and
immunoreactive
so to pick some of these attractive you
out in the weight
and it is a big positive way to slow in
a few is good so happy network
this has nice to repeat itself
differently respect to the weight you
get this product to the visible
in activity and so that route is gonna
show up a lot in the learning
cuz that derivative is how you change
the energy at the Combine configuration
visible
mutants the probability of a
combine configuration given the energy
function is he to the minus the energy
that among
aggression normalized by partition
function and if you're into the property
for particular visible Victor
after some overall the hidden factors
that might go with it and
that's the problem visible to if you
want to change the weights to make this
probability higher
you always need to lower the energies of
combinations invisible vector
and the hidden back to the would like
with it and raise the images all other
combinations
see decrease competition the correct
Maxim like good learning rule
that is if I want to change the way so
as to
I'm increase the low probability this
network would generate the back to the
when I let it just sort of fantasize
things like to believe in is a nice
simple form
it's just the difference in two
correlations so even though it depends
on all the other way
its it shows up as this difference the
correlations and
what you do is you take your data you
activate
units this to cast by units you can
reconstruct
because I expect that this is a Markov
chain you want for a long time to you've
got me started
and then you measure the correlation
that with the correlation here
what you really doing is saying by
changed to a simple push into that
I'm lowering the energy this visible
backed
with whatever hidden victory chose by
doing the opposite
here I'm raising the energy things I
fantasize
and so what I'm trying to do is believe
in the data not believe in what model
believes it
eventually this correlation with the
same as that one in which case nothing
on
because I believe in the data it turns
out you can
get a much quicker learning algorithm we
just gone done it again
you take this difference correlations
them
justifying that is hard the main
justification is it works
um and it's quick the reason these
modules interesting
the main reason interesting is you can
stack them up studies
the company injuries are not gonna go
into it works very well
to training module then take the
activities are the features actors
treat them so they were data and train
another module on top of that
so the first module is trying to model
what's going on in the pixels by using
the speech in sectors
and the checks written to be highly
correlated the second model is trying to
model correlations among peach victims
and you can guarantee that if you do
that right
every time we gotta love legal battle
with the data actually can guarantee
that the first time you got level
for the level where you can guarantee is
that there's a band on how good you
might love the data is
every time you add another level that
band improves
if you got it right having got this
guarantee that something good is
happening is we have more levels
with them violate all conditions that
mathematics and just add more levels and
so that ok way
has been a good things can happen and
then we justified by the fact that good
things do happen
this elisa's to learn many lies a
feature detectors entirely unsupervised
just a model structure in the data once
we done
you can get that except in machine
learning conference because you have to
discrimination to be accepted notion
conference so once you've done that you
add
some decision units to the top and you
learn the connections
discriminative Lee between the top their
features in the decision units
and then if you want you can go back and
find June all the connections using
backpropagation
that overcomes the limits a
back-propagation which is
there's not much information labeling it
can only learn on labeled data
these things come on on large amounts of
unlabeled data
after they've learned then you add these
units at the top
and back propagate from a small amount
labeled data
and that's not designing the features
actors anymore
as you probably know Google design
feature detectors is the art of things
and you'd like to design features actors
based on what's in the data
not based on having to produce labeled
data so the idea back propagation was
designed your piece that is so you could
be getting the right answer
the ID case design your features actors
to be good at Motley whatever's going on
in the data
once you've done that just ever so
slightly fine-tune them so you better
getting right answer
but don't run use the answer to design
feature detectors
and you're sure binges lap is done lots
a work showing that
this gives you better minimizing Justin
backpropagation
and what's more min completely different
part of the space
so just to summarize this section
I think this is the most important slide
in the talk because it says what's wrong
with Neil machine learning
up to a few years ago what people in
machine learning we're trying to do is
learn a mapping from an image to label
and I will be a fun thing to do if you
thought that images in labels arose in
the following way:
the stuff in it gives rise to images and
then the images give rise to the labels
given the image the labels don't depend
on stuff
but you don't really believe that you
believe that if the label something like
the parity if the pixels in the image
where you really believe is the stuff
that gives rise to images
and then the labels ago with images
because the stuff not because the image
so the cow in a field in use a cuddle
now if I just say County you
you don't know whether the cows brown or
black co upright or dead
or far away if I share your images the
care you know listings
so this is a very high bandwidth this a
very low bandwidth
and the right way to associate labels
with images is to first learn to invert
this high bandwidth path
we can't really do that cuz the gym
workspace the first or you look at than
you see things
and it's not like it might be kinda
might be an elephant it might be a
lecture theatre
basin you get it right knee all the time
and so we can but that pathway
having learned to do that we can learn
what things are cold
but you get the concept work am NOT from
the name
from seeing what's going on in the world
and that's what we're doing
men later say setting the label
now I need to do one slight modification
to the basic module
which is I had binary units as the
observables
now we want to have living units with
casino is
so we just change the energy function a
bit and the energy now says
I gotta kinda parabolic containment here
each of these linear visible units
has a bias which is like his mean we
would like to see here
moving away from that costs in an issue
problem is the negative local guys in
costs it and then the input the comes
from the hidden units
this is just me I H JW I J
but these have to be scaled by the
standard deviation at the
guessing that
the if I ask if a different route that
with respect to visible activity
them when I get is HJ Wijk divided by
the Sigma right
and that's like an engine gradient and
what the visible unit does when you
reconstruct
is it tries to compromise between
wanting to sit around here
and wanting to satisfy this energy
gradient say goes to the place where
these two great in single opposite
and you have that's the most likely
value and then you have guys in my
judgment
so without small modification we can I
deal with
real money data with binary latent
variables and we have an official
money out ridden its approximation
acting like it
so we can apply to some
so is a nice speech recognition task has
been well organized by the speech people
where there's no data base coat imminent
it's all very well to find casper phone
recognition
wear what you have to do is your
commercial window speech
you have to predict the distribution the
probability
for the central frame the various
different phones
actually each frame is modeled by three
statesmen so the
beginning middle and end so you have to
predict retrain
is its is at the beginning middle align
the beach the possible fines
the 193 those things if you give it
a good distribution so focused on the
right thing
that all post-processing will give you
back
where the phone in Bangor should be and
what your phone are a tease
not so very standard some people use try
from models
um where you can buy for models which
isn't quite as powerful
um so now we can test how good we are
a taking 11 Princess Peach is 10
milliseconds per frame but he trains
looking like 25 min second speech
and predicting the phone at the middle
frame
we use the standard speech
representation which is Mel capsule
coefficients
the 13th those in their differences and
differences differences
and we feed 'em into one of these deep
thats
so his your input 11 frame 239
coefficients and then I was away when
the student this
and he actually believed what I said so
he thought adding lots and lots been
less was a good idea
I'm stopped to but yet it also mean less
all unsupervised so all these green
connections
learned without any use for the labels
he used to bottle like bear so the
number red connections will be
relatively small
these are not these have to be learned
using discriminative information
um and now you back probably get the
correct answers through this home at
for by today on a GP you bored um
or a month comical and
it does very well studies the best phone
rato was
23 percent but the important thing is
whatever configuration used how many
could mess as long as you're plenty
whatever width whether uses pot like a
not he gets between 23 and 24 percent
says very robust to the exact details
I'm any less
I want their the best previous result
intimate
for things that didn't you speaker
adaptation with 20 4.4 percent
not with averaging to get a lot two
models so
this is good
with yep common ailments um
so we only training 123
one to 3 we training in about 20 million
mites
$20 million weights is about
I'm 2 percent to the cubic millimeter
cortex
them so this is a tiny brain that's
probably all you need to bring
recognition
is are differences in double differences
vehemence season good
that's a very good question could just
again at the end extremely good question
because
the recently put the differences in
double differences so they can model a
date with a diagonal covariance
Matri we are trying to convince model
pic a new car model fact that
overtime two things tend to be very much
the same
without modern conveniences unless you
actually put the differences in through
the day turn you what are the
differences directly
so allows you to use a model the Concord
because they're insists
later on we gonna show you model it can
cope with ovarian cysts
and then we gonna do declines with age
if you do
which is throw away the mockups
representation news about a workstation
speech
yeah he said that's me that something is
i cant so the new idea is to use a
better kinda module
this majority works pretty well right
you know it does well opinion
recognition it does well with other
things
econ mode multiplicative interaction is
very well
it can model anything I'm with enough
training data
but is not happy modding multiplies
multiplies all over the place
um I'll show you a bunch place where you
build
mice he's the sort of Maine example why
you need multiplies
suppose I want to from a high level
description of an object
the name that the shape and these poses
size position orientation special on a
generator parts an object
I want to be related correctly to each
other I could use very accurate talk
time model
the says knowing square nannies place
prime I generate
each piece in exactly the right position
I'm require high bandwidth
or I could be sloppy and I could say I'm
gonna generate decide
not answer is a representation the
distribution where the site might be
on generate corners and other sites and
their own a bit sloppy
if I picked one thing from each
distribution it would make a nice quite
but I could also top-down specify how
these things should be pieced together
in fact I can specify Markov Random
Field
says what goes with what and then I can
clean this up
knowing these distributions and pick a
square like that
because I might sometimes because where
there's a slightly different orientation
were slightly different size but it'll
be a nice clean square because I know
how I think go together
so that's a much more powerful kinda
general model
and that's what we want to learn to do
and so we can meet
hidden units appear to specify
interactions between visible units here
as opposed to just specifying input to
this Williams
there's an analogy for this which is
if I'm in office and there's a bunch of
soldiers and I want to stand in the
square
I could get my GPS mike is a soldier
number
one stand these GPS coordinates and so
do number two standard these GPS
coordinates
nothing is enough digits are getting
nice neat rectangle
work as a soldier number one stand
refuge here
and then soldier number two whole drama
out the stand this distance from Saudi
number one and that's a much better way
to get in the rectangle
will cost far less communication so what
you doing is you're downloading
roughly where people should stand and
then how they should relate to each
other
we have to specify the relations not
just where they should be
that's what we'd like in a powerful her
rocker generative model
so
we're going to aim to get units in one
layer
to say how units in the lab low should
laterally interact
when you're generating its gonna tonight
you don't need to worry about those with
her classroom track is when you
recognize me when you're generating you
do
um to do that we're going to need things
cool third audibles machines
with a three-way interactions so teri
Sinofsky point act
a long time ago that we have an energy
function like this
but this was the in this was a these
just buying
wheels and we could probably write an
injunction like this where three things
on track to have a 308
and if you think about the three things
now hey
stated k is acting like a switch when K
is on
effectively have this weight between I&J
when case of
is what disappears and it happens
every which way because this metric so
using an energy function like this
we can allow one thing to specify had
two other things should interact
so each in Munich is best for home
Markov random field over the pixels if
you want
that so begins to make you worry cuz my
girlfriend appeared as we're proud
president
and if you start counting indices here
if you have
end of the season and have those known
to those you get NQ
to these parameters which is rather lot
if you were willing to using key
parameters you can I make networks and
look like this
Spurs I have two images I want to model
how images transform overtime
and let's suppose I'm just moving random
dots around
have a pan around dots not translate
well
if I see that dog and I see that that
some evidence for a particular
translation
suffered a big positive way there
this triangle interruption that big
three way then when this
this the wrong they'll say it's very
good to have this Kyle
up in Iceland state if I also see this
paradox
I'll get more votes that this guy should
be on I'll turn this Kyle
if however this picture went to hear
about this guy and if this picture also
into the habit
this guy so these guys gonna represent
coherent translations of the image
and it can be able to use the three-way
to take two images
and extracting units represent the
coherent translation
it also be able to take the pre image in
the translation
and computer which pic so should be on
here
now we gonna do is take that basic model
I'm gonna fact right it
gonna say I got the three weights I got
too many of them
signing in to represent each three-way
as the product 23
to wait things I can infuse these
factors
each factor is gonna have these
these this many parameters which is just
um per factor it's just a linear number
parameters
if I'm about n factors I end up with any
and squared is these prime
these weights and if you think about how
pixels transforming an image
they don't do random permutations it's
not this because then that would cause
him
pixels do so the consistent things so I
don't really need and key parameters
cuz I'm just trying to model is fully
consistent transformations
which is limited number I should be able
to in many less printers
and this is a way to do so
that's going to be a new energy function
you can't buy stamps
one way of thinking about how in morning
wat is I want these
this tensor three-way weights if I taken
out a product due to factors like this
I'll get a matrix that has rank 1 figure
3 lacked a product
or get a 10 so that has run and if I now
add up a bunch of Kansas like that so
each factor in
which path specifies a ring on tensor by
coming up a bunch of them
I cannot let me tensile I if I use and
squared factors
phasing me n factors I can model nice
regular tense this but i ka model
obviously permutations that's what we
want if you are so how does imprints
work now
inference is still very simple in this
model so here's a factor
his the weights connecting it to say the
pre image
his the ways connecting it to the post
image is the weights connecting it to
the head units
and to do inference what I do is this
was only have that one factor I would
multiply the pixels by these weights um
at all add up so I get a summit this
vertex
I do the same here I get a summit this
vertex and I multiply these two sons
together to get a message trying to send
to the hidden units
and has that message goes to the hidden
unit I multiplied by the way to my
connection
so what the hidden unit will see is this
weight
times the product these two sons and not
is the derivative the energy with
respect to the state that this would
which is what he's no to decide whether
to be on or off he wants to go into what
are the state will love the image
and all the hidden units remain
independent even I got these multiplies
so this is much better than putting in
another state casting binary unit
if I produced gas turbine unit in fear
the hidden units will cease to be
independent in prince who get tough
but this way with the deterministic
factor that's taking a problem these two
sons
inference remains easy the learning also
remains easy
so this is the message that goes for
factor
to him unit H and that message is the
product that we got it is to know that
is
problems the computer on the pre-match
in the post image
and the way you learn the
wat on the connection from fact after
Muniz H
is by changing the way so as to lower
the energy
when you're looking at data and raise
the energy when you're constructing
model we're just reconstructing things
from the community got
date and those energy drink it just
looked like this they just the product
of the state Supreme unit
and the message goes to it when you're
looking at data
and stated that in unison message goes
to when you're looking at samples from
the model
reconstructions so still nice pairwise
learning
so everything is paralyzed still um
so you might they didn't bring
now if we look at what one of these
factors does when I show random dopant
to translate
then we can look at the weights
connected to the free image
and that's a patent weights wear white
is a big positive way
blacksburg make the point that would
have learned a great in connecting it to
the pre-match
Mistral integrating correct to post
image with a hundred fact is I show you
what role England
so those two hundred factors
connecting um these are the receptive
fields
factors in the pre-match remembers
looking at translating dots
and these are the factors in the post
image
NEC's basin and the free basis in its
land to translate things by about 90
degrees
and that's a very good way of handling
translation mathematician say things
like
the free basis is natural bases for
modeling translation I don't really know
what that means but
this land the free basis I'm on if your
attentions and learn a different basis
so this a basic lands rotations
she learns about you when yang
I'm apps which
a spaces for tations
arm one other thing you could do is
train it just on single don't plan to
the translating the case your way
and then tested it on
two overlaid dot patterns the
translating different directions
is never seen that before its only been
trained incoherent mation
we're gonna tested on Transpo school
transformation
in order to see what it thinks
room wit rainy unsupervised is no labels
anyway we never tell about the motions
on
we need somewhere seeing what is
thinking so we had a second hidden layer
the looks at the hidden units for
planning transformations
and it's fairly sparse so the unisom a
second inlet
will be choosing to particular actions
have motion
meant to see what is thinking we take
the
directions as units like weighted by how
acted as units no
and I'll tell you what direction it
thinks it see now when you show it
transformation when you look at those
units in the second hidden
if the two missions within about 30
degrees it sees a single motion at the
average direction
if they be on but they should be sissies
to deformations and what's more they
rappelled from each other
that's exactly what happens with people
so this is exactly how the brain works
I'm there's gonna be a lot I kinda
reasoning in this talk
I'm going on two time series models now
so we'd like to you
model not just static images for example
like a modern video
to be in with gonna try something a bit
simpler arm
when people do time series models you
would
nearly always like to have a distributed
nonlinear representation
but that's hard to learn so people tend
to do
dumb things like hidden Markov models
all in and Customs
which either give up on the distributed
or on the
nonlinear but a easy to do imprints
what we gonna come up with is something
that has the district and the nonlinear
and is easy to do imprints but the
learning algorithm
isn't quite right but it's good enough
it's just an approximation commencement
and the inference also is ignoring the
future and just basing things on the
past
so here's a basic module missus just two
way
interactions this is the restricted both
machines visible units
hidden units here are the pre
um previous visible frames these are
going to be linear units
and so these blue connections
conditioning
the current visible values on previous
and that runs
in a linear way such cold water
aggressive model
the hidden units here gonna be binary
him units they also condition on the
pieces
frames and learn easy easy in this model
what you do is you take your observed
data
and then given the current visible frame
given the previous visible frames
you get into today units they're all
independent given the data
so you can separately decide what states
should be in
once you pick states for them you know I
reconstruct
the current frame using the input you're
getting from previous frames
using the top dining for you going from
the units after reconstructive knee then
activate the music and
you take the difference in the power
status sex with data here reconstruction
to run these weights and you take the
difference on leaked images these guys
we date with reconstructions to get a
signal that you can use to learn these
weights
these weights so it's Manning's
straightforwardness just depends on
differences and you can look more like
this
of you learned it
you can generate from the model
by taking some previous frames
these imports the condition imports in
effect
fix the biases these to depend on the
previous frame so is there a dynamic my
sis
and then with the spices fix just go
back and forth
for a while and then pick up right now
and that's you an extremely generated
Nikica so we can generate from online
says none so we can see what it believes
sorry 0 with going back no week going to
go back more certain time
I I just got lazy with the power
One Direction week ago from case to to
high-level models
that is having learned this model where
these venues all independent given the
date
we could say what I done as I turned
visible frames
in Dunedin friends and it turns out you
can get a better model if you take these
hidden frames
a model what's going on here and now you
put in conditioning connections between
frames
and more him units the data conditioning
the don't
interact with humans and you know this
model then you can prove that if you do
this right
then you get a better more to love the
original sequences
or your improve abound on the model of
the original sequence
signals a less like that when you have
more lies it generates better Ryan go in
a different direction
um
I'm she had with 3-way connections and
we can apply it to
motion capture data so you put
reflective markers on the joint check
got something for eight cameras you
figure out where the joints are in space
you know the shape the body say go back
through that figure the joint angles
and then the freemen base is going to
consist of 50 numbers
about 50 numbers which are joint angles
and
the translations and rotations at the
base of the spine okay so imagine we got
one is manikins you seen Hot Shot
Windows
European stock in the base responding
and we can move around
and rotate im using this pain and you
can also weaken his legs and arms
okay and what we wanted to do is ask me
move around we want to do with his legs
and arms
so is put a piece to be stationary on
the ground in the hope is to be walking
the better we loose like just right is
to translate his pelvis
otherwise is put will appear to skate on
the ground and we're gonna model him
we can do i hark a model I could show
you all we can do three or more like
this
where week additional six earlier frames
is occurring visible from his your basic
both machine
except that it's no wonder these three
way things were these are factors
and we have a 10 men style variable so
we have taken with tenet the style in
the training it
that's a semi-supervised arm it learns
to convert that one event representation
into a bunch rely you features
many uses real value features has won
the imposter factor
more the fact is really doing is saying
these real money features
are modulating the weight matrices the
use for conditioning
and also this weight matrix use in your
13 on your mobile
so these a modulating an autoregressive
model
that's very different from switching
between autoregressive models is much
more powerful
yep so we gonna have dated someone
walking in various different styles
style style a book yeah said
the history would
yes said
yeah yeah the rights on the connections
will tell you which rims come from
right in the earlier model the two blue
lines
they differ matrices and their different
weights up
it just came to light right just yes
we another was as direct connections
from
all six previous frames to the company
for determining the country
me
well the were when you were computing
with the fifth Prime Minister
right but when we computing this spring
we have their connections okay
so we now gonna trying this model it's
relatively easy to train especially in
GP board
and then we can to generate from it so
we can see so but learned
and we can judge if it's doing well by
weather think sleep on the ground
me
I online
we'll get there I'm 3
he is a normal walk maybe
mister winning okay
says generated from the Motley deciding
which direction to turn in
means deciding um you know
heat needs to make yes i'd like you the
inside like and so on
um if we've
we have one model but if we flipped the
style label
to say um gangly teenager
he definitely looks
awkward right we will be in there some
I think this is a computer science
student
my main reason for thinking that is if
you ask into graceful
looks like this
and that's definitely see through peer I
good you
now now I think this was to not like to
be very good
I'm you can ask him to walk softly like
a cat we are asking the model a present
i'd
the model looks pretty much like the
real date to the real data obviously the
fee to plant it better
but notice he can slow down the speed up
again
water aggressive models can't do things
like that what are aggressive models
have a biggest I can value thus I think
bigger than one in which case explode
where it's more than one in which case
they died the way you came alive is by
keep you keep injecting random noise
so they stay alive and that's like
making a horse walk by taking a dead
horse and jiggling
its kinda is not good I'm
now
he doesn't have any model the physics so
in order to do these kinds stumbles I
had to be stumble similar to that in the
data
but when he stopped in which somebody
did when
is entirely determining um
we could make into a sexy won't be a
problem not interested in that
you want answered
chicken westerns with chicken
unless dinosaur and chicken
that's a blend
maybe switch his Google Earth puts get
this is probably a blend
this is doing sexy walk
and then you flip label to normal when
you flip it back to sexy it's never seen
any transitions because oh one more
thing we can do with the transitions
there the couple those from
wanna be in style styles yep
yep now you can also give him any more
labels when you train
you give its speed stride length all
sorts of things then you can control it
very well
okay so we can on time series at least
for fifty dimensional data
and obviously won't want to do is apply
that to video but we have nothing
set for some very simple cases
the last thing on your show use the most
complicated use these three models
one way of thinking of it
so that's similar to the previous uses
is we take an image you make two copies
of it
but they have to be the same and then we
insist the weights the go from a factor
to this copy is the same as the weights
ago from the fact this disc
so I equals JW I feel because the region
inference is still easy
impact inference he will consist of you
take these pixels times these weights
to get a weighted sum and then you
square because this is going to be the
same way tits
temperance consistent take a linear
filter square its output
and send it by these works to hidden
units that's exactly the
model call the Arlington energy model
she is right and when the filter
since been proposed both by vision
people by Adelson Bergen a long time ago
in the eighties and by neuroscientists
senior scientist attract a simple cells
a quick thinking about and look at
what polynomial the iPod is that they're
important
and young than a berkeley says it's
between 1.7 2.3
and that means to right I'm
so this looks quite like model so will
propose drop quite different reasons and
he just dropped time to take a three-way
energy model in fact rising at
the advantage we have is that we have a
learning are going through these weights
now only have a general model
mom so now we can model covariances
between pixels
and the reason that's good is well is
one reason is good
I'm spose I ask you to define vertical
edge
most people say we love Escalade you
some this light on the side document
site
well not now maybe it's like i'm this
i'm not come outside being a
well could be lighter p.m. don't end
there in Dhaka P in like 10 American
or it could be a texture each scan code
might actually be disparity age
arm well managed to be motion this side
main mission that's a that's a little
edge to
I'm so vertical edges are big assortment
of things more all listings have in
common
is a vertical edge is something where
you shouldn't do horizontal
interpolation generally image
horizontal interpolation works very well
a pixel is the average if it's right
left neighbors
pretty accurately or sold occasionally
breaks down replacing brakes times with
the political edge
so a real abstract definition virtual
wage
is a breakdown of her simple
interpolation and that's what I models
are gonna do a heating unit
is going to be putting in a min
interpolation
and it's actually the town of Cicero
smudge ink
when that breaks down is gonna turn off
so one less thing it is this
if this hidden units here
is on it puts in a weight between pixel
I'm pics LJ
the sequel to arm this way
times this wait times its weight okay
since these okay combat I'm
so these controlling
effectively the mark from the field
between pixels so we can model converts
is nicely
because the hidden units are creating
correlations invisible units
reconstruction is now more difficult we
could reconstruct one image given the
other image that will be my shin
but if you want to reconstruct them both
make my den to call
gets to be harder so we have to use a
different method called hybrid want to
comment essentially you start with the
data was
and let it wander away from where it was
but keeping both images the same
I'm not gonna go in type 1 comment but
it works just fine for doing the right
thing
and the 101 colors used just to get the
reconstructions
the running out in just the same as
before and what we gonna do is we're
gonna have
some hidden units that by using the
three-way interactions to model prevents
it from pixels
another hidden in this is just one means
so we cool
for meaningful than siegel is macao p.m.
arm
he's an example of what happens after is
learned
on black and white images his image
punch
he's its reconstruction of the image
patch
if you don't had no is which is very
good from the
mean and covariance hidden units his
sister Cassie
reconstruction which is a pretty good
but now we can do something funny you
were gonna take the
activations are the covariance units the
things are modeling which pictures in
the same as which other pixels
and we'll keep those but we're gonna
take the expressions in the mean unit so
we threw those away
and pretend that the means for the
pixels look like this
let's take this one place we tell all
pixels have the same value said these
which my stock
and in nine tries to make that
information about means
30 me this information i covariances
which is that these guys should be the
same
very different from these guys and so it
comes up with the reconstruction looks
like that
where you see is taking this doctor from
blurted across this region
if we just keep it four dots like that
and the covariance matrices got from
there it'll blow those dots I'm
to make an image that looks quite like
that one so this is very light was cool
to
kinda watercolor model images where you
know but with a bang resign
in just a rough sketch in the colors are
the regions amid all it's fine to us
because we saw the slave the Kalibangan
is to the actual
where the ages of um if you reverse the
colors are these
produce the reverse image because the
covariance doesn't care at all about
signs that things if you look at the
filters
uelman's the mean units which offers a
recovery in regions
learn these blurry filters and by taking
some combination of a few dozen times
you can make more less whatever colors
you like anywhere very blurred their
smooth blurry and multicolored on
you can me roughly right colors the
covariance units nine something
completely different
so these what the filters line and
you'll see that
those factors they learn high-frequency
black might ages
and then a small number
them turning to low-frequency color it
is the right the red green or yellow
blue
I'm what's more when you make it home a
topographic map
using a technical describing the next
slide you get this color blog this low
frequency kinda blog in with the
low-frequency black Michael Kors
and that's just what you said among his
brain cream
if you don't among his brain you see
these high physical to his orientation
changes smoothly as you go through the
cortex
tangentially and you see these
low-frequency callebs
most your scientists thought I'm that at
least must be an act
well this is saying is no just the
structure
images is and the idea for a truck
traffic map
is enough to get this but doesn't mean
it's not innate
just means it doesn't need to be so the
way we get there
topographic map is by
this global connectivity from the pixels
to the factors
so the fact is really are learning local
filters the local focused on of color
then gradually learn to be exactly black
and white
then those local connectivity between
the fact is in the head units
so when these hidden units will connect
to a little square off
practice and then induce the topography
and the energy function is such that
when you turn off wannabes hidden units
to say smoothness no longer applies
I'm you pay a penalty and you'd rather
just pay the penalty once
answer to thanks is gonna come on at the
same time
is best to connect them to the same unit
saying pay the penalty once
so that'll cause similar factors to go
to several places in here
me a topographic map
for people who know about modeling
images
um so far as I know nobody has yet
produced a good model a pact is a color
images
that is a generative model would
generate stuff that looks like a real
date
so his a model with London 16 by 16
color images from the Berkeley database
and his things generated from and they
look pretty similar
nice partly a trip is the color balance
here is like the color balance and that
makes you think this summer
but is partly real I mean most to these
a smooth patches
referee uniform color as almost to these
the few more these scrutinize
but you also get these things where you
get fairly sharp edges
see get smooth this then shop age than
most with this like doing real date
you get things like owners here we're
not quite there yet but this is the best
model is applied to the color images
and this causes modeling both the
covariance and the means
says caper saying what's the same as
what as well as
what the intense desire
you can apply for doing recognition
so this is a difficult object
recognition task where those
eighty million unlabeled training images
novel with these passes but prices as
the crisis
they were collected by people MIT is
called the tiny images database
the 32 by 32 color images but it's
surprising what you can see nothing to
do with a single image
and since the biggest mobile we're going
to use has about a hundred million
connections
but about .1 to the cuban a racial
cortex in terms number parameters
and so we have to somehow give a
computer model
some way of keeping up with the brain
which has a lot more hardware so we do
it by giving a very small right now
we say suppose the temple was only 32 by
maybe we can actually do something
reasonable
so as you see there are a lot of
variation if you look at the that's as
close up across to reach
this is a much more typical picture but
and
it's hard to tell the difference in
these ten categories
particularly things like dear course we
do breaches a very similar categories
like truck car deer and horse
people pretty good at these people won't
make very many errors that's partly
because these were hand labelled by
people
I'm so that even even people make
summers
we only have 50,000 training examples 5
as in each class
and 10,000 test examples could we have
and label them
but we have a lot on trade unlabeled
data so we can do all those pre training
a lot on mobile data
and then take our covariance units and I
mean units
and just try doing multinomial logistic
regression on top with those
or maybe add another hidden landed on
top of that
so well my career as i text me David
I'm since he worked in young because lab
yeah actually took small patches Monday
model and then
stratum across the mission replicate
them so the semi compositional
and then took the hidden units have all
these little patches and just
concatenated them
to make a great big picture of I'm
11,000 units
which both the means and the and the
covariances
and then we cannot use that as I
features see how well we can do
and we're going to compare it with
various other methods
so the surface compared to just take the
pic cells
unduly just aggression on the pixels
decide on the 10 classes
you get 36 percent right if you take
just features we should develop by
troubled people MIT
which meant to capture what's going on
in the image quite well but if any
low-dimensional
arm yet 54 percent so much but in pixels
if you take a normal rpm which has
living units with case in noisy input
variables and binary hidden units
and then uses binary hidden units to
castigation
you get sixty percent if you use
what are these IBM's with both the units
like these ones for doing the means
and then these units with three-way
interactions among the covariances
you get sixty nine percent as long as
you use a lot of these factors
and if you can learn an extra hidden
layer right-sizing
senators that time that Sandra million
$600 million connections you done that
that's fine because he's on supervised
me just landed on what's the data
you get up seventy percent not the best
results so far on this database
one final thing
you can take this model was developed
for image patches
and the stupid in phoneme recognition
just took that code
and appointed to look spectrograms which
is sorta more close to what dick would
like to see some you're not using all
the small capsule stuff which is
designed to throw away stuff you think
you don't need
and get rid of the correlations instead
you can take david has also correlations
in
but we got a model can deal with that
stuff I'm and
the first thing George tried to be the
28th
on which was follows a thousand in units
on top with this
I'm got 22 percent correct is that
correct which was the record
for phone recognition on the 28 database
where you know
trying to do in model adapted to each
speaker
and then week later when he did that to
the bad news more frames to thank Tony
1.6 percent
so this all this stuff was designed to
do vision it wasn't designed to the
phonemes
and if we treats phoneme recognition is
just a vision problem on the lock
spectrogram
we can wipe out the speech guys I'm
at least on small the Kaveri another
student is now
Microsoft see if this were complete
recovery as well
yes yeah right
me
we can give them you better tools we can
get the pneumatic tools
say his phoneme recognition over the
years
bankrupt from the eighties got 26 one
person correct
over the next twenty years or so they
got the country 4.4 percent
using that as the one you respond socal
much official
am we've now got and 31.6 percent
blessed with a few mobile homes is about
15 percent I don't know much about how
they did
assessment um we're but we nearly a
third of the way from artificial tree
I'm so we the two more ideas in with her
okay
I'm done infringed
a nap
yeah
you mentioned he did
movie moving
is
by using
within the good good
you yes he did indeed announce that
what he didn't announce was his wrist
his
he's got a spectacular result against on
235 events arm
what he didn't announce was this two
tricks involved
want ricky is to use a big net with lots
of layers and the GP you called
Patrick by itself won't give you thirty
five errors
the second trick which was surprising
dates
but you're a Microsoft impact which is
to put a lot of work
into producing distortions have the data
so you have not some not some labeled
data
see take a label the measure to and you
just Austin clever ways that make is to
look like a to
be translated so people get down to
about
forty years get
said it's already planted so you get on
to unit on July four tiers
by doing these distortions what he did
was even better distortions more of them
and a much bigger net and a GP you got
from 4235
which is impressive is how to make any
progress at
but it won't work unless you have lotsa
labeled data
and what's the disguise thing is the
work went into if you look in the paper
it's almost report is just back prop
except when you get to the section how
the generational sector labeled data
where this very careful things like it's
a one or seven they
any rotated a certain number degrees but
it is something else irritated more
degrees
I know she's referee for this paper but
I don't mind in knowing
I'm i think is very important work but
he should emphasize that
um they had to have labeled a tizzy that
network into distortions so for me the
lesson that paper is
when we had small computers um
you should put your effort into things
like weight constraints
so you don't have too many parameters
you only got a small computer
as computers get bigger and faster
you can transfer your effort from the
senate turning the weights to get like
em was doing
in the early days poor you effort into
generating more distortions
see conjecture prior knowledge in the
former distortions
and that's much less competition
efficient with the computer is fine
and is more flexible so I think that's
the lesson up
the
dead
he them
think that you in bed them cortex here
as expected property those vision
trip the problems you know
by it I'm maybe
be quicker to say the problems we not
been applied but
company her
but I mean okay
let me say what the main limitation if
this is true vision we've got
least 10 billion euros for doing this
you released billion anyway
probably ten billion and even though we
got that many neurons
and but tend to the 13 connections could
envision we still have a red notice got
a very small so be the size my thumb
that arm's length
and so we still take almost everything
and don't look at it and the essence a
vision is not to look at almost
everything
intelligently and that's where you get
all these funny illusions
we don't see things some we have to do
that in these models these models are
completely crazy
your computer vision is completely crazy
almost all that because they take a
uniform resolution image
quite a big one like it has my house and
they try and deal with
all at once with filters all over the
image and if they gonna do selection
they either do it by running of the face
detect everywhere
with no intelligence all they do so
interest point detection
and a very low level to decide what to
attend what we do is we think takes
somewhere
then on the base is what I retin-a gives
us with these big pixels on the edges
more pics in the middle
we so decide what we're seeing where to
move next
by the second author fixation with a pic
sitting very intelligently
and the essence of it is a vision is
sampling um
is not processing everything and that's
completely missing from what I said
now in order to do that you have to be
able to take what you saw our way
sorting remind them
not to multiply so this module within
the month price is very good at
combining what some ways to integrate
information at the time
and that's when the things we worked on
but that's probably the biggest thing
missing but that is an example of
having a module is quite good but now
is never good enough so you have to put
it together over time use many times
and that's what sequential reason all
this stuff are so
basically as soon as people become
sequential we're not moving at all
with more than what you can do in
hundred milliseconds and so that was
missing
but I believe that to model a sequential
stuff we need to understand
what is a sequence all is a sequence
that these very powerful operations
and we better shape now to try model
sequential AI
than we were if we didn't know what a
primitive operations mister printer
operation was just deciding whether to
symbols are the same
we're gonna be active luck for
understanding how people this country
the
good
you with
said
I'm still processing that quite big hug
right
right I'm making the point that people
think 15 quite difficult I'm
not to be good I would love to do that I
have not got a clue how to do it
and you'll notice that in old-fashioned
II that you use to point out on your own
at people
the income to qualify so forget it
nowadays when the old a graphical models
they didn't mention that anymore cuz a
graphical models have difficulty with
the two
some people scuffles least you're
awesome people track yet some people to
the most to the graphical models
like five years ago them to qualify as I
and so
a pretty good division mining would be
what you can do without having to do
with release first get problems like
I would love to know how we deal with
that but I'd so yeah I'm gonna give up
on that right now
good
label no extra would be
yes in yes intimate that's what we have
intimate all examples
we have labels is still is a big win to
the pre-training
well your judgment Hooper hasn't tried
yes with all these distortions do in
pre-training neither soon called in on
marriage just recently sis
where he tries things like that he tries
distortion zionist
and he uses special distortions it is
I'm
and the fact is distortions help a lot
but if you pre training that helps some
more too and benches results just
revenge is results suggest that
um return you will get use a different
part of the space even if you have all
this label date
sickly one thing that needs to be done
is to try the pre-training
mundo israel's you don't have to have
the pre training but I bet you would
still hopes and about you it's
more efficient to it's fast because
briefings are to be fast you don't learn
very good model
get lotsa it reaches the starting from
there
I think you'll do better than he does
just starting from random
and fast that's just a prediction you
might even get down to 34 s
the problem with amnesties
there a solo you can get significance to
me is really nice that way the ninety
well see higher rates CQC differences
the up
said
the
rising
sorry didn't understand the question we
have a limited time with them
after for me
is there any Israel
nothing not
the cannot deal with some
the car model housed rights but
if sir what happened fifteen time steps
ago
really tell George should have now and
only tells your staff night doesn't tell
you what's happening to meet you 14
times tax
just contains information across 15 time
steps without having the signatures more
time scales
you come pick up on that because he's
not gonna hidden a four pack router
before back in our room potentially
could pick up on that allowed actually
count
I'm said
probably walk behind the box and
comes out the other side not over a long
time scale my
unless you say that there's a memory
involved where you go back to previous
guestbook a pic now it is true that when
you build a multi-level one which you
can do with three elections as well as
the two connections
at every level you getting a bigger
times bankers your time window
says going further back into the past
which level to get a bit I got class
just a living
you say
him how much unlabeled the
to train the different levels change
like this is just you number waits for
as you go
levels thing sad ones sort of
important thing to say about that which
is that if you modeling high-dimensional
tater you trying to build an
unsupervised model of the date
you need many less training examples
then you would have thought
if you use to this country learning when
using discriminative learning
the stoop me very few bits her training
case to constrain the parameters
demand constrained you can you promise
for training case is number bits it
takes to specify the ONS
not the number this is expressed by the
import so we then missed you get 3.3
bits per case
if your modeling the image the number
bits per case is a number to take space
for the image
which is about a hundred bits so you
need far fewer cases
parameter number saying is your modeling
much richer thinks
and so each case is given much more
information
so actually we can typically model many
more prime system we have training cases
discount to people on used to that many
less primes me a pic cells
many more than training cases and in
fact
he only used by two million cases for
doing the image stuff
he wasn't enough it was over 30 he
should have used more um
but he was getting 100 million
parameters but the
basically the annual family is um
many less primed is the number total
number pixels in your training
data but you can typically use many more
parameters the number trying cases
and you can't do that with northeastern
Thailand
now if you do that when you start to
school to train
it quickly improve things and then very
quickly if it's so you have to stop it
early
okay
went Scully who